Okay, so in this video, let's just discuss
some agile release plan, just some
high-level aspects of agile release
planning.
Now, in Agile and the
Agile world, the closest
thing to a project is known as a release.
Remember, a release is made up of many
iterations, many sprints.
So typically, a release would be three to
nine months.
It doesn't have to be, but just as a very
simple, typical example, a release would
be three to nine months and within a
release you have several sprints,
several iterations, right?
And each sprint is typically two to four
weeks.
And again, it doesn't have to be,
but, you know, just as a general rule,
two to four weeks is an iteration or a
sprint.
Now, during release planning then,
what are we doing?
Right.
What are we actually planning during
release planning?
All right?
Well, first of all, what are the roles?
The main role, right and an agile project
is you have a product owner who is the
voice of the customer they represent the
customer you have the team facilitator
right who is the servant leader and you
have the agile team the cross-functional
team right with the t the t-shaped skills
right the cross-functional team now
collectively then during the agile release
plan they're going to be determining
things like how many sprints are we going
to have during this release remember
release is like a project
right so how How many
sprints are we going to
have, how many iterations?
How long is each iteration, each sprint
going to be?
Is it two weeks, four weeks, that kind of
thing?
What is our definition of done?
What does it mean for the work to be
complete?
Plus, within the sprint as well,
right?
What are the various different milestones
we may have within the sprint,
daily standard meetings and so and so
forth?
They're also going to be working on user
stories, right?
You're collecting the
requirements, creating
user stories, seeing
what user stories we have.
The product owner is going
to be prioritizing those user
stories to come up with a
backlog, with the product backlog.
And then the team themselves,
the Agile team, we'll be looking
at these user stories, some
of them would be high level.
Remember, you have the Epic, right?
An Epic is a very high-level user story.
You're breaking it down into features for
the user stories before you configure out
how longer each user
story is going to take by
breaking them down
into individual activities.
So, the team themselves are
going to be doing a high-level
relative estimate of these
user stories or of these epics.
So this is all done, again,
during release planning, the
Agile Release Plan, we
need to understand all of that.
We need to come up with this at the
beginning, during the release planning,
we need to figure out what's
all the work, how are we
going to separate all the
work and so and so forth, right?
Now, even though Agile
allows for change, the
whole idea of Agile
is it allows for change.
It doesn't mean you don't plan,
right?
Agile is not we figure it out when it
happens, or we figure it out if it
happens, we'll figure it out, you know,
as we go along.
That is not a plan.
Even in an Agile, you are going to have a
plan.
We're going to plan how long our sprints
are going to be, what user stories we
could be taking in Sprint, how we're going
to prioritize and so and so forth.
Sure, things can change.
But you still need to have a basic plan.
Now, few other terms then, right?
The closest thing to a schedule,
right, in an agile environment,
is something called a product roadmap,
right?
In an agile environment, you don't really
have a true schedule.
You don't determine
initially these are all the tasks
that need to be performed
and these are the dates.
So the critical past stuff that we talked
about earlier, or the critical past stuff
that are in the video, the early videos,
they relate to predictive.
Critical path does not always work in an
agile environment.
The closest thing to a schedule in an
agile environment is a product roadmap.
A couple of other terms you'll come across
is a product vision, and the product
vision is generally written in the project
charter, documented
in the project charter.
So yes, an agile project has a project
charter as well.
And it basically defines
what is to be accomplished,
the reason for doing the
project and so and so forth.
So again, Agile Release Planning,
right?
So within an Agile release, you have all
of these different sprints in there.
We need to figure out what we're going to
be performing in each sprint, how many
sprints we're going to be having,
and, you know, how we're going to break
down the backlog items and so on and so
forth.
Now, another term I want to mention that
you may not come across on the exam,
but you should know this anyway,
and it's called the spike, right?
And for the exam, they'll ask either
architectural or risk spike.
But they're very similar to one another.
And basically what a spike is in an agile,
in an agile world, is this basically a
specialized type of user story,
right, or a specialized type of sprint,
an additional sprint, right?
And it's used for further
investigation of unknowns, unknown
activities or tasks that haven't
been estimated yet, right?
We need to find some additional
information, right?
So the product owner and the team and the
team facilitator, again, during Agile
release planning, they're going to be,
you know, figuring that out.
So you may have some additional user
stories or rather some even some
additional sprints
altogether, right, at the
beginning to identify some
of these unknowns, right?
So we can have, or
rather so the team can get a
better understanding of
the requirements, Right.
Requirements are more complicated,
better understanding of the requirements,
trying to identify, reducing any risks of
technical, you know, whatever the
technical approaches, new technology,
and so and so forth.
So it's a very simple example here.
The team does not have enough knowledge of
this new technology.
This new technology they're
supposed to be using or this
new technology that they're
supposed to be delivering.
They don't have enough knowledge of that.
So before they can start thinking about
all the user stories and what user stories
are going to be implemented and what user
stories are going to be broken down and,
you know, what tasks to perform each user
story.
They need to understand what they're even
delivering.
They need to understand the technology in
the first place.
So they may create an additional spike,
right?
So they have an architectural spike or a
risk spike.
They may create an additional spike,
so which is basically like an additional
user story or it might be an additional
sprint altogether at the beginning,
right, as part of release planning to
actually determine all of this.
So that's what a spike is, just in case
you come across this term.
And again, generally, it'll be done at an
agile release, or at least the agile
release planning, that's
when you're going to
be determining whether
or not you need a spike.